Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Collection, 1876-2020 and undated, bulk 1950-2020 RL.10006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Files, 1902-2020; undated
  - Administrative Files, 1958-2017; 1
    - General Working Files, 1964-2017; undated; 5
      - Correspondence re: permission to use video footage, 2017 (Box 73)
      - Directories and biographies, circa 1980s (Box 200)
      - Event invitations and programs, 2012 (Box 200)
      - Event invitations and programs, 2013, 3 folders (Box 200)
      - Event invitations and programs, 2014 and undated (Box 200)
      - Fogg Museum promotion, 1980 (Box 200)
      - Form letter: Dear PR please send books for review, undated (Box 200)
      - France, hotel receipt, 1983 (Box 200)
      - Guest list and RSVP list, Spielvogel Database, 2001 May 1 (Box 200)
      - Host/guest theme chart, undated (Box 200)
      - India, 1982 (Box 200)
      - Inside New York's Art World Artnews review, 1980 (Box 200)
      - Internship form letters, 1983 (Box 200)
      - Internship resumes, 1980-1983 (Box 200)
      - Internship sources, 1981-1982 (Box 200)
      - Invitations--sample designs, 1975-1981 (Box 200)
      - Italy, 1978-1985, 2 folders (Box 201)
      - Job materials, 1964 (Box 201)
      - Library of Congress materials, 1998 (Box 201)
      - Loose notes and contacts, circa 2010 (Box 201)
      - Loose printouts of emails, online resources, notes, 2013 (Box 601)
      - Los Angeles, 1982 (Box 201)
      - Magazines ordered through Backer and Spielvogel, 1983 (Box 201)
      - Marymount Manhattan College/Pat Koch Thaler, 1980 (Box 201)
      - Master: best press releases from each project, 1977-1983 (Box 201)
      - Master lists--flow charts, 1984, folder 1 of 2 (Box 201)
      - Master lists--flow charts, 1984, folder 2 of 2 (Box 202)
      - Master lists of videotapes, 1986, 1992 and undated (Box 202)
      - Materials for press kits, 1969-1976 and undated (Box 202)
      - Materials in 1970 appointment book, 1970 (Box 202)
      - McCall pay stubs and correspondence, 1968 (Box 202)
      - Membership and business cards, various visitor badges, 2000s-2013 (Box 601)
      - Midwest, USA, 1984 (Box 202)
      - Mixed biographies, undated, 2 folders (Box 202)
      - The New York Times spring art showcase, 1978 (Box 202)
      - Notes, clippings, and printed materials, 2006-2007, 3 folders (Box 202)
      - Notes, clippings, and printed materials, 2008, 3 folders (Box 203)
      - Notes, Clippings, and printed materials, 2016-2017 (Box 72)
      - Office business expenses, 1974-1975 (Box 203)
      - Office memos and faxes to Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel, 1991-1992 (Box 203)
      - Office supplies, 1982 (Box 203)
      - Others' resumes, 1997 (Box 203)
      - Portland, Oregon, 2011 (Box 203)
      - Press kit example, 1983 (Box 203)
      - Press releases, 1985 and undated (Box 203)
      - Press release materials, 1980-1983 (Box 203)
      - Professional and academic recommendations, 1978-1982 (Box 203)
      - Proposals, donations and bills, 1977-1980 (Box 203)
      - Publications, undated (Box 204)
      - Requests for help and resumes, 1991-1993 (Box 204)
      - Rizzoli contracts, 1975-1982 (Box 204)
      - Rizzoli press releases, 1980-1981 (Box 204)
      - Sample announcements, 1983 (Box 204)
      - Smythson stationery, 1993 (Box 204)
      - Standard letters, 1977-1978 (Box 204)
      - Tennessee, 1981 (Box 204)
      - Melany Terranova Recommendation, 2012 (Box 204)
      - Texas, 1970-1981 (Box 204)
      - Tiffany's program, 1987 (Box 204)
      - Video collection rental/donation, 1977-1987 (Box 204)
      - Videotape master lists, 1982 (Box 204)
    - Phone Logs, 1977-2005; 6
      Predominantly messages and memos taken by others while Diamonstein-Spielvogel was away. Arranged chronologically by month and year.
      - Phone logs, 1977 Mar.-June (Box 204)
      - Phone logs, 1977 May-Aug. (Box 205)
      - Architectural League, 1980, 2 folders (Box 205)
      - Phone logs, 1980 (Box 205)
      - Phone logs, 1980-1981 (Box 206)
      - Phone logs, 1981-1982 Feb. (Box 207)
      - Phone logs, 1982 Mar.-Nov. (Box 208)
      - Phone logs, 1982 Dec.-1983 Sept. (Box 209)
      - Phone logs, 1983 Sept.-1984 May (Box 210)
      - Phone logs, 1984 June-1985 June (Box 211)
      - Phone logs, 1985 July-1986 Apr. (Box 212)
      - Phone logs, 1986 June-Aug.; 1992 Jan.-1993 Mar. (Box 213)
      - Phone logs, 1993 Mar.-June; 1994 Feb.; 1995 May-Oct. (Box 214)
      - Phone logs, 1996 Feb.-Dec. (Box 215)
      - Phone logs, 1997-1998 June (Box 216)
      - Phone logs, 2003 Oct.-Nov; 2005 Oct.-Nov. (Box 217)
  - Ambassador Files, 1990s-2017; bulk 2000-2002; 2
    This subseries comprises materials pertaining to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's from activities and interests related to her residency in Slovakia, stemming from the appointment of her husband, Carl Spielvogel, to Ambassador to that country from 2000 to 2001. Formats documenting her work include clippings, notes, correspondence, printed materials, photographs, and some artifacts. Diamonstein-Spielvogel's work was two-fold: she aided her husband in his position as ambassador, and she turned to documenting and supporting the art, culture, and quality of life of Slovakians, becoming especially concerned with issues relating to the status of women and the Roma people in Eastern Europe. Some materials are in the Slovak language.
    Highlights include materials pertaining to her work on The Plight of the Roma, an international conference in 2004 discussing the history of the Roma and addressing the racial and social discrimination and human rights concerns of their current situation with keynote speaker Hillary Clinton.
    Some related audiovisual materials are located in the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials Collection.
    - Ambassador Calendar, 2000-2001 (Box 220)
    - Ambassador Carl Spielvogel and Ivan Miklos sign, undated (Box 220)
    - The Ambassador's Review, 2012 (Box 220)
    - Ambassador Bill Richardson party, 1997 (Box 220)
    - Ambassador trip to London, 2002 (Box 220)
    - Amber Room, St. Petersburg, Russia, undated (Box 220)
    - American art in the Ambassador's residence, 1998 (Box 220)
    - Art in the heart: a celebration of Slovak culture, 2000 (Box 220)
    - Articles about the Diamonstein-Spielvogels/Bratislava, 2001 (Box 220)
    - Brass plate from Slovakia, undated (Box 593)
      (8x11 in.)
    - Bratislava articles and photographs, 2000-2001 (Box 220)
    - Celebrate Diversity: Slovakia, 2012 (Box 220)
    - Chihuly art book, Slovak Republic, 2001 (Box 220)
    - Chihuly exhibit in Bratislava, 2000 (Box 220)
    - Clinton recommendation, 1999 (Box 220)
    - Clippings, notes, printed materials, 2004 (Box 220)
    - The Corcoran Gallery, 2002 (Box 220)
    - Correspondence journal, 2000-2001 (Box 220)
    - Department of State flag, undated (Box 593)
    - Embassy Ljubljana, Executive Office guide, 2009, 2 folders (Box 601)
    - Foreign Service Institute: A Reader's Guide to the Slovak Republic, 1997 (Box 220)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies, 1999 (Box 220)
    - Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies, Tenth Anniversary, 1996 (Box 221)
    - General materials, 2016-2017 (Box 72)
    - History of United States Diplomacy, 1996 (Box 221)
    - Hryc, Andrej, undated (Box 221)
    - Inside the Embassy, 2002 (Box 221)
    - International clippings, 1998 (Box 221)
    - International Visitor Leadership Program, 2010 (Box 221)
    - Lubomira Slusna and Rainer Franz wedding, 2011 (Box 221)
    - The Magic of the Middle of the Danube Honor for Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel, 2001 (Box 221)
    - Materials, 2003-2004 (Box 221)
    - Meda Mladek dinner, 2001 (Box 221)
    - Mission of Slovak Republic to the United States, 2003 (Box 221)
    - Photos from unknown European location, 2000? (Box 601)
    - The Plight of the Roma correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box 221)
    - The Plight of the Roma international conference, 2004 (Box 221)
    - The Plight of the Roma poster, undated (Box 598)
    - Protocol for the Modern Diplomat, Foreign Service Institute, 1998 (Box 221)
    - Radio Free Europe, 2000 (Box 221)
    - Roma clippings, 2001-2004 (Box 221)
    - Roma conference, correspondence and research, 2004 (Box 221)
    - Roma conference, guest list, 2004 (Box 221)
    - Roma conference, New York, correspondence, 2004 (Box 221)
    - Roma Women's Forum, 2003-2004 (Box 222)
    - Romany for Society, 2004 (Box 222)
    - Spielvogel-Diamonstein Lecture on Culture and Foreign Policy, 1999 (Box 222)
    - Spielvogel-Diamonstein Lecture on Culture and Foreign Policy, 2000 (Box 222)
    - Slavik Division, New York Public Library, 2001 (Box 222)
    - Slovenska Republica Shield, undated, (9x9 in.) (Box 593)
    - Slovak-American Cultural Center, 11th annual Slovak ball, 2003 (Box 222)
    - Slovak PEN Center, 2004 (Box 222)
    - Slovak PEN Center, undated (Box 222)
    - Slovak Philharmonic Orchestra, Jessye Norman, 2001 (Box 222)
    - Slovak Republic ambassadorship, 2001 (Box 222)
    - Slovak Republic correspondence, 1984-2001 (Box 222)
    - Slovak Republic correspondence, 2001-2005, 3 folders (Box 222)
    - The Slovak Spectator, Slovakia 10th Independence, 2003 Jan. 13-19 issue (Box 223)
    - Slovakia clippings, notes, printed materials, 2004, 2 folders (Box 223)
    - Slovakia correspondence, 2004 (Box 223)
    - Slovakia - Europe on a small scale, 2004 (Box 223)
    - Slovakia is Ready event, 2003 (Box 223)
    - Slovakian street scene in watercolor, gift from Andrej Durkovsky, mayor of Bratislava, between 2002-2010, (9.5x11.5 in.) (Box 583)
    - Tokyo lectures, 2006 (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State Ambassadorial Seminar, 2009, 2 folders (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State Ambassadorial Seminar, Office of Civic Rights, 2009 (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State Art in Embassies Program, circa 1990s (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State Broadcasting Board of Governors, 2008 (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State diplomatic reception rooms, 2009 (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State diplomatic reception rooms, 2016-2017 (Box 73)
    - United States Department of State, Friends of Art and Preservation in Embassies, 1999 (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State, memorandum on public outreach/embassy briefing, 1997 (Box 223)
    - United States Department of State Swearing-In Ceremonies, 2009 (Box 224)
    - U.S. Mission to Slovenia, 2009 (Box 601)
    - United States Strategic Plan for International Affairs, 1999 (Box 224)
    - Visegrad Group, V4 Through My Eyes, 1991-2011, photography exhibit and program, 2011 (Box 224)
      Color publication celebrating 10th anniversary of founding of Visengrad Group, composed of Poland, Hungary, Czech Republic, and Slovakia. Includes photographs from exhibit, comments from photographers, and cultural programs.
  - Awards, 1975-2018; undated; 3
    Contains certificates, artifacts, honors, letters of endorsement, and other materials such as correspondence and photographs relating to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's awards. This does not represent a full account of Diamonstein-Spielvogel's honors and awards. Those regarding specific projects, organizations, or other activities are included with those materials in other series in the collection. Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Original folder titles are retained.
    - The Acting Company Fall Gala honoring BLDS and Carl Spielvogel, 2018 Nov. 12 (Box 650)
    - American Institute of Architects Thomas Jefferson Award, 1993 (Box 224)
    - American Institute of Architects Award photograph, 2005 (Box 224)
    - American Institute of Architects nomination, 2005 (Box 224)
    - ArtsWestchester award, 2016 (Box 72)
    - ArtsWestchester award, 2017 (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Awards, various, presented to Diamonstein-Spielvogel (Box 591)
      Includes mayor's award from Southampton; pins and medals; other assorted small awards
    - Awards, various, presented to Diamonstein-Spielvogel (Box 613)
    - Awards, various, presented to Diamonstein-Spielvogel (Box 620)
    - Awards, various, presented to Diamonstein-Spielvogel (Box 621)
    - Bowne House Historical Society award, 2011 (Box 148)
    - Boymeetsgirlusa.com cloth bag in recognition of Diamonstein-Spielvogel's work with Help USA, undated (Box 589)
    - Certificates and awards, 1975-1994 (Box 224)
    - Certificates and awards (oversize), 1975-2012 (Box 178)
    - Chashama honors, 2012 (Box 224)
    - Citizens Committee of New York City award, 2010 (Box 224)
    - Clarion Society Gala honoring BLDS, 2019 Mar. 5 (Box 650)
    - Denver Business Improvement District tree plaque, undated (Box 650)
    - ELLY award, 2012 (Box 224)
    - Entrepreneurial American Leadership Award, 2008 (Box 224)
    - Fountain Gallery gala, 2008 (Box 616)
    - Golden Medal of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the Slovak Republic, 2003 (Box 224)
    - Help USA humanitarian award, 1998 (Box 224)
    - Honorary degree, Maryland Institute College of Art, 1990 (Box 224)
    - John Jay Medal, 2012 (Box 224)
    - Letters of endorsement, 1977-1982 (Box 224)
    - Long Island Museum certificate of appreciation, 2012 (Box 224)
    - Longwood Center for the Visual Arts, 1994-1995 (Box 224)
    - Longwood College Honors, 1995 (Box 224)
    - Manhattan Awards, 1999 (Box 224)
    - New Millenium Humanitarian award, HELP U.S.A. publications and reports, circa 1998-1999 (Box 588)
    - New Millenium humanitarian award to Barbaralee and Carl, 1999 (Box 224)
    - North Carolina Order of the Long Leaf Pine award, 1983 (Box 224)
    - Governor Pataki's Commission honoring achievements of women, 1999 (Box 224)
    - Pratt Institute honorary degree and commencement photographs, 2010, 2 items (Box 224)
    - Pratt Institute Founder's Dinner, correspondence, 1994, 2 folders (Box 225)
    - Pratt Institute Founder's Dinner, itinerary, 1994, 3 folders (Box 225)
    - Pratt Institute Founder's Dinner, press clips, 1994 (Box 225)
    - Pratt Institute Founder's Dinner, speech and program, 1994 (Box 225)
    - Pratt Legends award, 2008 (Box 616)
    - Purchase College honorary degree and commencement speech, 2017 (Box 72)
    - Purchase College honorary degree, 2017 (Box 73)
    - Ralph C. Menapace Memorial Award, 2012 (Box 225)
    - State of New York legislative resolution honoring Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel, 2010 January (Box 225)
    - United States Holocaust Museum vice chairman appointment, 1991 (Box 225)
    - Westchester County Proclaims Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Day, 2012 (Box 225)
    - Women's City Club Civic Spirit Award, 1998 (Box 225)
    - Women's Civic Service Award, 1997-1998 (Box 225)
    - Historic Districts Council Landmarks Lion award, 2011 (Box 148)
  - Engagements and Interests, 1966-2019; undated; 4
    Contains correspondence, clippings, photographs, slides, notes, printed materials, speeches, proposals, and other manuscript drafts related to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's engagements and interests. Highlights include materials pertaining to the Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, held at the National Gallery of Art, where distinguished artists such as Joel Shapiro discuss the genesis and evolution of their work.
    Audiovisual materials located in the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials Collection.
    - About New York CUNY materials, 1998 (Box 226)
    - Ackerman (Mona) dinner, 1992 (Box 226)
    - Address on State of the City, 2013 (Box 226)
    - American Craft, 1981-1983 (Box 226)
    - American culture speech, circa 1972 (Box 226)
    - American Foundation of Royal Academy of Music reception with the Princess of Wales, 1989 (Box 226)
    - American Institute for Imported Steel, 1978 (Box 226)
    - Artes Graficas Panamericanas (AGPA) International Art Exhibit, 1981 (Box 226)
    - Article ideas, 1983 (Box 226)
    - The arts salute Peter Valone, 1997 (Box 226)
    - Aspen Music Festival, Aspen Ambiance and Tent, 1979-1980 (Box 226)
    - Baruch College Advanced Management Program, 1975 (Box 226)
    - Benefits, 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 226)
    - Bicentennial Commemorative Medal, 1976 (Box 226)
    - Big Apple Award, 1998 (Box 226)
    - Block party, 1988 (Box 226)
    - Boardroom Consultants Inc., 1977-1979 (Box 226)
    - Brooklyn Academy of Music King and Country Benefit, 2016 (Box 633)
    - Brooklyn Youth Chorus Academy, 2005-2009 (Box 226)
    - Carter Brown and National Gallery, 1973-1979 (Box 226)
    - Brownstone Revival Committee, 1991 (Box 227)
    - Dave Brubeck party, 1992 (Box 227)
    - Budget- Polshek/Spielvogel, 1980 (Box 227)
    - Leo Castelli, 1976-1978 (Box 227)
    - Leo Castelli, Jasper Johns Exhibit, 2010 (Box 227)
    - Rand Castile, 1971-1982 (Box 227)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System Lamp Unto My Feet agreement, 1975 (Box 227)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System Lamp Unto My Feet- Women's Rights, Women's Roles, 1974 (Box 227)
    - Celebrating American Craft, 1997 (Box 227)
    - Channel 13 on air auction, 1982 (Box 227)
    - Chasama gala 2012 (Box 227)
    - City Ventures Fund, 1987 (Box 227)
    - Richard Clurman, 1974-1975 (Box 227)
    - Columbus Jubilee Commission, 1989 (Box 227)
    - Stephen Conn, 1980-1982 (Box 227)
    - Conversation with Frank Stella, 1999 (Box 227)
    - Corcoran fashion fall, 1992 (Box 227)
    - Craft is a Verb Exhibit, 2000 (Box 227)
    - Creating Tomorrow, 1998 (Box 227)
    - Cultural affairs interview program proposal, 1996 (Box 227)
    - Cultural calendar proposal, 1987 (Box 227)
    - John Cushman proposal, 1966 (Box 227)
    - Dallas area rapid transit designs, 2003 (Box 227)
    - Detroit Institute of the Arts, 1979 (Box 227)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Mel Bochner, 2007 (Box 227)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Andy Goldsworthy, 2005 (Box 227)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Ann Hamilton video podcast (email), 2012 (Box 602)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Martin Puryear, 2008 (Box 227)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Ed Ruscha, 2003 (Box 227)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Joel Shapiro, 2012 (Box 227)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Leo Steinberg, 2003 (Box 227)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: general correspondence, programs, etc., 1997-2008 (Box 616)
    - Diamonstein-Spielvogel Lecture Series, National Gallery of Art: Carrie Mae Weems, 2015 (Box 633)
    - Don't Let them Tear the Old Place Down, 1975 (Box 227)
    - Duke University, Public Policy and the Arts, 1978 (Box 227)
    - Esalen Institute benefit draft, circa 1970 (Box 227)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2008-2009 (Box 602)
    - Event invitations, 2010 (Box 228)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2010-2011 (Box 602)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2012 January-November (Box 602)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2012 December and undated (Box 602)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2013 January-March (Box 602)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2013 April-June (Box 602)
    - Event invitation and programs, 2013 July-August (Box 603)
    - Event invitation and programs, 2013 September-December, 3 folders (Box 603)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2014 and undated (Box 603)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2015, 4 folders (Box 633)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2016, 2 folders (Box 633)
    - Event invitations and programs, 2016-2017; 22 folders (Box 638)
    - Events, ticket stubs, programs, and playbills, 2018-2019; 10 folders (Box 651)
    - Events, tickets, programs, invitations, 2019-2020; 6 folders (Box 654)
    - Event materials, 1988-1995 (Box 228)
    - Feast and fetes, Irish party, 2009 (Box 228)
    - Fietzek request for Weiner interview, 1999 (Box 228)
    - Flags, 1994 (Box 228)
    - Fleischman, Joel, tribute, 1991 (Box 228)
    - Foreign Student Service Council, 1982 (Box 228)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt for Freedom Park, 2012 (Box 228)
    - The Friends of City Center of Music and Drama, 1972-1973 (Box 228)
    - The Future of Preservation Maryland Institute Symposium, 1989 (Box 228)
    - Miriam and Henry Goldberg Memorial Lecture, 1994 (Box 228)
    - Governor's Arts Awards - Judith Jameson, 1998 (Box 228)
    - Guest lists, 1970-1971 (Box 228)
    - Habitat Galleries - Dale Chihuly, 2001 (Box 228)
    - Hanes, R. Philip Jr., 1979 (Box 228)
    - Hardy, Holzman, Pfeiffer Associates, 1989 (Box 228)
    - Hartman, William, letters and photographs, 1966 (Box 228)
    - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1983 (Box 228)
    - Heritage Trails -- My Benefit Reception, 1998 (Box 228)
    - Hirschfeld, Al, exhibit, 2009 (Box 228)
    - Historic Easton, 1980 (Box 228)
    - Historic Preservation Talks in Japan in 2006, 2012 (Box 228)
    - History Happened Here, 2005 (Box 228)
    - Hollywood Athletic Club, 1991 (Box 228)
    - Home Again proposal, 1993 (Box 228)
    - Huffington, Arianna, birthday, 2010 (Box 228)
    - Hufstedler, Shirley, 1980 (Box 228)
    - Human Rights Watch, Chen Guangcheng and Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel, 2012 (Box 228)
    - Ideas folder, 1983 (Box 228)
    - Ideas in progress, 1987 (Box 228)
    - Imagine New York, summary report, 2002 (Box 229)
    - Inside Art World Two, 1994 (Box 229)
    - Interface, 1974-1980 (Box 229)
    - International Center of Photography, 1981 (Box 229)
    - International Exhibits Foundation, 1981-1982 (Box 229)
    - The Jerusalem Foundation, 2011 (Box 229)
    - Jewish Women's Foundation, 2005 (Box 229)
    - Johnson, Philip, 90th, 1996 (Box 229)
    - Karz, Millenium dinner, 1998 (Box 229)
    - O. U. Kid LLC operating agreement, 2001 (Box 229)
    - Living Legends, Harry N. Abrams Inc. Publishers, 1995 (Box 229)
    - London National Ballet party, 1995 (Box 229)
    - Longwood College graduation, 1995 (Box 229)
    - Lorenze, Albert, rapidgraph rendering, undated (Box 229)
    - Maloof, Sam, 1987, 2005 (Box 229)
    - Management Women, Inc., 1978-1979 (Box 229)
    - Marymount Manhattan College benefit, 1983 (Box 229)
    - Meier, Richard, Corcoran Gallery, 1996 (Box 229)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, gifts, 1986-1987 (Box 229)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, Vatican exhibit, 1983 (Box 229)
    - Metropolitan Opera subscription, 1976-1980 (Box 229)
    - Meyer, Karl, party, 1970 (Box 230)
    - Microgallery, Ltd., 1983 (Box 230)
    - Mint Museum Agreement, 2011 (Box 230)
    - Montebello, Phillippe de, 1978-1983 (Box 230)
    - Ms. 40 year anniversary, 2012 (Box 230)
    - Musica Sacra, 1981-1982 (Box 230)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, "The First 100 Years," 1976? (Box 230)
    - Museum of Graphic Art, 1966 (Box 230)
    - National Building Museum blueprints, 2002 (Box 230)
    - National Gallery of Art: Chuck Close conversations with artists, 1999 (Box 230)
    - Neanderthal party, 1996 (Box 230)
    - Nevelson, Louise, 1989 (Box 230)
    - Nevelson Chapel support, clippings, correspondence, 2012; 2019 (Box 652)
    - New Jersey Historical Society, 1988 (Box 230)
    - New York Community Trust guidelines for grants, 1999 (Box 230)
    - New York Convention and Visitor's Bureau, undated (Box 230)
    - New York housing contest, 2003 (Box 230)
    - New York, New Visions: Rebuilding of Lower Manhattan, 2002 (Box 230)
    - NY1 drafts, 1990-1992 (Box 230)
    - New York Preservation Archive Project, Bard Birthday Breakfast Benefit, 2015 (Box 633)
    - New York State Council on the Arts, 2008-2012, 4 folders (Box 230)
      Includes files re: her 2008 nomination and a 2012 council meeting.